Mike Matthews

Address April Cottage Date of Birth: 11/01/62

Fir Tree Avenue Email: email@mikematthews.org.uk
Stoke Poges, SL2 4NN www: http://mikematthews.org.uk

Personal Profile

A senior sales individual with 20 years of successful selling of enterprise-level software and services solutions, principally in the Financial Services, Telco and Hi-tech sectors. Solutions sales trained, I am comfortable operating from board level down with a customer-centric, profit-driven approach. My wide range of experience has been gained in an international context across many markets, and within both direct and indirect sales models.

Principle Achievements

I have made significant customer gains within each of my roles, for example:

- Closed first new name customer outside US (Summer Mobile / CapeTown, SA) for Synchrony at Cincom
- Closed first sale of a Process Portal (combination of WS Process Server + WS Portal) into SMB segment for IBM UK
- Successful execution of Regional Systems Integrator initiative for ISV & Developer Relations at IBM UK
- Doubled size of pan-European Distribution business unit at MicroTouch Systems
- Win top annual international sales award at ParcPlace-Digitalk & Intersolv
- Closed first >100+k sale via channel at Informix

Career History

IBM Senior Sales Executive 03/01 – present

• Initially responsible for sales via Global Systems Integrators (e.g.; Deloitte & LogicaCMG), I moved onto direct sales into south-east UK territory of GB business unit, and then onto application-led sales via major ISVs (e.g.: ESRI & Cincom Systems). Solutions ranged from B2C commerce portals to B2B trading platforms involving complex sales cycles in excess of 6 months, often working at board level with both Line of Business & IT departments being key in influencing the decision making process. My solution skills required working knowledge of Customer Experience Management and back office application integration, such as web services.

2010–11: <u>Director, Customer Experience Solutions</u> – at Cincom Systems (on secondment from IBM) – responsible for sales of Synchrony solution across EMEA- closed first new name account with Summer Mobile & ABSA Bank in South Africa; pioneered development of solution for real-time, intelligent agent guidance within contact centre.

2008– 09: <u>Client Executive, ISV & Developers</u> – executed worldwide initiative for Regional Systems Integrators in UK, which I single-handedly drove to over-achievement in terms of new recruits, news skills enabled & technologies adopted. This resulted in 4 successive quarters of Excellent Awards. Also delivered over half the new OEM deals within peer group & responsible for winning major new ISVs such as ESRI and Cincom Systems

2006- 07: <u>Software Sales Manager, Focus Accounts, South-east UK General Business</u> - achieved 130% transactional revenue target (\$3.4mill vs. \$2.6mill target); closed \$1mill ELA with RR Donnelley (Astron) & \$500k with ACE Insurance, which was first ever sale of a Process Portal in a UK General Business account. Also negotiated licence compliance deal with Groupama Insurance.

2001–05: <u>Software Sales Executive, Global Systems Integrators</u> – responsible for sales to and thru Deloitte, LogicaCMG, KPMG – achieved competitive winback in Deloitte Consulting repeatable solution "Realtime for WebSphere", which generated >\$2.5mill revenue, and \$750k win at VISA UK in its first fiscal period, thereby winning Integrator of Year award for best repeatable solution; other highlights include \$1.1mill resale win for Tivoli at VISA, \$2.6mill win at Co-op Financial Services, Set/Met score of 1 (exceeded all expectations) for customer satisfaction, and a total of \$3.3mill direct resale revenue via Deloitte in 2005.

iE (Intelligent Environments) plc

UK Alliances Mgr

01/2000 - 02/01

- * leading supplier of eCommerce front-end applications for credit cards, ISAs and Insurance
- * responsible for a \$3m channel sales business unit with 3 direct reports
- * personally recruited a new channel of consultancies (Deloitte), SIs (Logica, CMG) & ISV's (BoNY, Fiserv).
- * achieved \$3.5 million against a target of \$3million

MicroTouch Systems

EMEA Distribution Group Manager

02/98 - 12/99

- * leading supplier of touchscreen technology
- * responsible for one of the three business units with an annual turnover of US \$13 million
- * 8 direct reports across UK, France, Germany, Italy and Spain
- * implemented a new Monitor Alliance Program to target the major branded display vendors (EIZO, LG and iiyama)
- * grew Distribution Focus Group from \$7 million to \$14 million and 3 direct reports

ParcPlace-Digitalk

European Sales Manager

11/94 - 01/98

- * leading vendor of object technology based on Smalltalk
- * responsible for entire distribution channel across Europe and the Middle East
- * recruited distributors and VARs in France, Spain, Italy, Belgium, Netherlands, and Scandinavia
- * grew revenue to an annual turnover in excess of \$2.5 million
- * top international sales person award in fiscal 1995 (\$1.6 mill against \$1.2 mill target)

- * leading supplier of 4GL development tools and RDBMS
- * responsible for generating "pull thru" revenue from major ISVs in the UK
- * closed Informix's first ever licence sale in excess of \$100k generated via a UK partner
- * promoted from covering the second-tier 50 resellers to the top 25 ISV partners

Intersolv plc PVCS International Distribution Manager 10/90 – 08/92

- * leading integrated CASE vendors and AD/Cycle partners
- * responsible for sales of market-leading PVCS version control software
- * ran a network of national distributors and dealers across continental Europe and Scandinavia
- * achieved top International Sales person achieving in excess of 120% of target

Uniplex Ltd International Sales Executive 07/87 – 09/90

- * office automation software for the UNIX operating system
- * Distribution account manager for France, Belgium and Holland
- * managed Bull and Philips as world-wide OEM accounts
- * 18 months initiating Uniplex's French subsidiary in Paris

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

•	1986-1987	Post Graduate Diploma in European Marketing Management Bucks Chiltern University, including Spanish & IT
•	1980-1984	B.Hons 2.2 – French Language & Literature University of Birmingham Thesis on role of gender in modern French
•	Sales Training	IBM Global Sales School; Solution Sales
•	Languages	Fluent French & working Spanish
•	Marital Status:	Married with 3 sons